Welcome to the final video of this Machine Learning class.
欢迎来到《机器学习》课的最后一段视频
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
We've been through a lot of different videos together.
我们已经一起学习很长一段时间了
In this video I would like to just quickly
在最后这段视频中
summarize the main topics of this course
我想快速地回顾一下这门课的主要内容
and then say a few words at the end and that
然后简单说几句想说的话
will wrap up the class.
作为这门课的结束
So what have we done?
那么我们学到了些什么呢？
In this class we spent a lot of time talking about supervised learning algorithms
在这门课中 我们花了大量的时间
like linear regression, logistic regression, neural networks, SVMs.
介绍了诸如线性回归 逻辑回归 神经网络 支持向量机
for problems where you have labelled data and labelled examples
等等一些监督学习算法 这类算法具有带标签的数据和样本
like x(i), y(i)
比如 x(i)  y(i)
And we also spent quite a lot of time talking about unsupervised learning
然后我们也花了很多时间介绍无监督学习
like K-means clustering,
例如 K-均值聚类
Principal Components Analysis for dimensionality reduction
用于降维的主成分分析
and Anomaly Detection algorithms for when you have only
以及当你只有一系列无标签数据 x(i) 时的
unlabelled data x(i)
异常检测算法
Although Anomaly Detection can also use some labelled data
当然 有时带标签的数据
to evaluate the algorithm.
也可以用于异常检测算法的评估
We also spent some time talking about special applications
此外 我们也花时间讨论了一些特别的应用
or special topics like Recommender Systems
或者特别的话题 比如说推荐系统
and large scale machine learning systems
以及大规模机器学习系统
including parallelized and rapid-use systems
包括并行系统和映射化简方法
as well as some special applications like
还有其他一些特别的应用比如
sliding windows object classification for computer vision.
用于计算机视觉技术的滑动窗口分类算法
And finally we also spent a lot of time talking about different aspects
最后 我们还提到了很多关于构建
of, sort of, advice on building a machine learning system.
机器学习系统的实用建议
And this involved both trying to understand
这包括了怎样理解
what is it that makes a machine learning algorithm
某个机器学习算法
work or not work.
是否正常工作的原因
So we talked about things like bias and variance,
所以我们谈到了偏差和方差的问题
and how regularization can help with some variance problems.
也谈到了解决方差问题的正则化
And we also spent a little bit of time talking about
同时我们也讨论了
this question of how to decide what to work on next.
怎样决定接下来怎么做的问题
So, how to prioritize how you spend your time
也就是说当你在开发一个机器学习系统时
when you're developing a machine learning system.
什么工作才是接下来应该优先考虑的问题
So we talked about evaluation of learning algorithms,
因此我们讨论了学习算法的评价法
evaluation metrics like  precision recall, F1 score
介绍了评价矩阵 比如 查准率 召回率以及F1分数
as well as practical aspects of evaluation
还有评价学习算法比较实用的
like the training, cross-validation and test sets.
训练集 交叉验证集和测试集
And we also spent a lot of time talking about
我们也介绍了学习算法的调试
debugging learning algorithms and making sure
以及如何确保
the learning algorithm is working.
学习算法的正常运行
So we talked about diagnostics
于是我们介绍了一些诊断法
like learning curves and also talked about things like
比如学习曲线 同时也讨论了
error analysis and ceiling analysis.
误差分析 上限分析等等内容
And so all of these were different tools for helping you to decide
所有这些工具都能有效地指引你
what to do next and how to spend your valuable
决定接下来应该怎样做
time when you're developing a machine learning system.
让你把宝贵的时间用在刀刃上
And in addition to having the tools of machine learning at your disposal
现在你已经掌握了很多机器学习的工具
so knowing the tools of machine learning like
包括监督学习算法和无监督学习算法等等
supervised learning and unsupervised learning and so on,
但除了这些以外
I hope that you now not only have the tools,
我更希望你现在不仅仅只是认识这些工具
but that you know how to apply these tools really well
更重要的是掌握怎样有效地利用这些工具
to build powerful machine learning systems.
来建立强大的机器学习系统
So, that's it.
所以 就是这样
Those were the topics of this class
以上就是这门课的全部内容
and if you worked all the way through this course
如果你跟着我们的课程一路走来
you should now consider yourself
到现在 你应该已经感觉到
an expert in machine learning.
自己已经成为机器学习方面的专家了吧
As you know, machine learning is a technology
我们都知道 机器学习是一门对科技 工业
that's having huge impact on science, technology and industry.
产生深远影响的重要学科
And you're now well qualified to use these tools
而现在 你已经完全具备了应用这些
of machine learning to great effect.
机器学习工具来创造伟大成就的能力
I hope that many of you in this class
我希望你们中的很多人
will find ways to use machine learning
都能在相应的领域 应用所学的机器学习工具
to build cool systems and cool applications
构建出完美的机器学习系统
and cool products.
开发出无与伦比的产品和应用
And I hope that you find ways
并且我也希望你们
to use machine learning not only
通过应用机器学习
to make your life better but maybe someday
不仅仅改变自己的生活
to use it to make many other people's life better as well.
有朝一日 还要让更多的人生活得更加美好！
I also wanted to let you know that this class has been great fun for me to teach.
我也想告诉大家 教这门课对我来讲是一种享受
So, thank you for that.
所以 谢谢大家
And before wrapping up,
最后 在结束之前
there's just one last thing I wanted to say.
我还想再多说一点
Which is that: It was maybe not so long ago,
那就是 也许不久以前
that I was a student myself.
我也是一个学生
And even today, you know, I still try to take different courses
即使是现在 我也尽可能挤出时间
when I have time to try to learn new things.
听一些课 学一些新的东西
And so I know how time-consuming it is
所以 我深知要坚持学完这门课
to learn this stuff.
是很需要花一些时间的
I know that you're probably a busy person
我知道 也许你是一个很忙的人
with many, many other things going on in your life.
生活中有很多很多事情要处理
And so the fact that you still found
正因如此 你依然挤出时间
the time or took the time to watch these videos
来观看这些课程视频
and, you know, many of these videos just went on
我知道 很多视频的时间
for hours, right?
都长达数小时 是吧
And the fact many of you took the time
你依然花了好多时间
to go through the review questions
来做这些复习题
and that many of you took the time
你们中好多人 还愿意花时间
to work through the programming exercises.
来研究那些编程练习
And these were long and complicate programming exercises.
那些又长又复杂的编程练习
I wanted to say thank you for that.
我对你们表示衷心的感谢
And I know that many of you have worked hard on this class
我知道你们很多人在这门课中都非常努力
and that many of you have put a lot of time into this class,
很多人都在这门课上花了很多时间
that many of you have put a lot of yourselves into this class.
很多人都为这门课贡献了自己的很多精力
So I hope that you also got a lot of out this class.
所以 我衷心地希望你们能从这门课中有所收获
And I wanted to say:
最后我想说 再次感谢你们选修这门课程！
Thank you very much for having been a student in this class.